David E. Ferro

Address: 11270 Apache Dr., Apt. 204 **Cell Phone**: (216) 258-6464

Parma Heights, OH 44130 Email: david-ferro@sbcglobal.net
: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-ferro-979152172/

LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-ferro-979152172/Portfolio:https://davidferro91.github.io/Bootstrap-Portfolio/index.html

GitHub: https://github.com/davidferro91

Summary:

Full-stack Web Developer able to use HTML, CSS, JavaScript (with a focus in jQuery), and node.js to create a variety of webpages. Eleven years of logic-oriented and problem-solving experience from college coursework, teaching high school mathematics, and coding bootcamp. Detail-oriented, ensure projects are completed correctly, able to stay calm under pressure, and transform abstract, complicated topics into an understandable description.

Technical Skills:

Front-End

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript (with a focus on ¡Query)

Back-End

- Node.js
- MongoDB
- MySQL

Other Programming History

Java (one semester in college)

Projects:

Night on the Town

https://davidferro91.github.io/GroupProject1/ https://github.com/davidferro91/GroupProject1

- Web-based application that is designed to provide the user with events, bars, and restaurants in any U.S. city of their choice for today or a future date
- Designed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Seat Geek API, Yelp API, Zomato API, Zippopatum.us API, and HTML-5 Geolocation

https://davidferro91.github.io/GifTastic/ https://github.com/davidferro91/GifTastic

GifTastic! Gif Generator

- Webpage designed to generate the user's desired GIFs using user-created buttons from typing a topic into the search bar, and then
- Clicking on the buttons generates the GIFs, and clicking on the images animates them
- Utilizes HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Giphy API

Trivia Game

https://davidferro91.github.io/TriviaGame/https://github.com/davidferro91/TriviaGame

- Trivia game webpage with a 30-second time limit to answer each of the ten questions that keeps a running tally of your score and shows you your results at the end
- Designed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and intervals for the timing

https://davidferro91.github.io/Word-Guess-Game/https://github.com/davidferro91/Word-Guess-Game

Word-Guess Game

- Classic hangman-type game that is browser-based using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (not jQuery)
- Dynamic webpage that reacts primarily to keystrokes, but also includes a button for clicking to reset their scores

Education:

October 2018 – April 2019

Case Western Coding Bootcamp

Cleveland, OH

- Learned front-end and back-end web development in a fast-paced bootcamp experience
- Earned A's on all homework and projects, especially those using JavaScript
- Utilized GitHub and Heroku for hosting websites

August 2008 – May 2012

Case Western Reserve Univ.

Cleveland, OH

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude earning a Bachelor of Arts degree with a double major in Mathematics and Teacher Education
- Earned an A in the Java Programming course
- Received ETS Recognition of Excellence on the Praxis Mathematics Content Knowledge test
- Member of the Pi Mu Epsilon Mathematics Honors Society CWRU Chapter
- Studied in the Case Western Teaching Program in conjunction with John Carroll University to receive Ohio State Teaching Licensure at graduation

Work Experience:

August 2012 – Present Horizon Science Academy

Cleveland, OH

High School Math Teacher

- Taught AP Calculus AB, Algebra II, Geometry, and Algebra I, Pre-Calculus, Trigonometry/ Differential Calculus, and Statistics
- Utilized technology in teaching, including Star Board, TI-84 calculators, document camera, and mathematics websites such as desmos.com and wolframalpha.com
- Served as 11th Grade Chair in 2013-2014, and 12th Grade Chair from 2014-2018
- Served as Master of Ceremonies for the graduations of the senior classes from 2016 to 2018 as well as on the Graduation Planning Committee
- Led multiple student organizations, such as Chess Club, Student Council, and Bowling Club

August 2015 – December 2017 Case Western Reserve Univ. Cleveland, OH Master Teacher/Adjunct Lecturer for CWRU Teacher Education Program

- Mentored teacher candidates in the CWRU Special Methods courses as they did observations, taught lessons (both mini-lessons and full-length lessons), and wrote reflective papers based on the classroom experience
- Met in monthly meetings with the teacher candidates, CWRU faculty, and Special Methods instructor in Reflective Triads where we discussed readings on teaching methods, techniques, and philosophy, as well as classroom observations and experiences, and the candidates' reflections

August 2011 – May 2012 Magnificat HS Rocky River, OH Pre-Student/Student Teaching

- Taught two AP Calculus AB classes and three Algebra I classes periodically from August through December and full-time from January through May
- Led a workshop during a faculty/staff in-service on creating presentations with the website Prezi
- Utilized Wikispaces and Smart Board technology within the classroom

Aug. 2010 – Dec. 2011 Case Western Reserve Univ. Cleveland, OH Calculus Supplemental Instructor

- Served as a supplemental instructor for Calculus I and II for Business, Economics, Life Sciences, and Social Sciences
- Led multiple weekly tutoring sessions and weekly recitation sessions
- Administered and graded tests and quizzes

References:

Contenza, Terri

Instructor

Department of Mathematics

Case Western Reserve University

Yost 330

Cleveland, Ohio 44106

(216) 368-6678

Email: cxb10@case.edu

Davis, Denise

Director of Teacher Education

Case Western Reserve University

11635 Euclid Avenue

4th Floor – Room 417

Cleveland, Ohio 44106

(216) 368-1505

Email: denise.k.davis@case.edu

Marencik, Joe

Faculty, Teacher Education

Case Western Reserve University

11635 Euclid Avenue

4th Floor

Cleveland, Ohio 44106

(440) 667-0593

Email: jjm203@case.edu

McKinley, Megan

Instructional Coordinator

Horizon Science Academy HS

6000 South Marginal Road

Cleveland, OH 44103

(216) 432-3660 x509

Email: mckinley@horizoncleveland.org

Nagelski, Denim

Math Department Head

Horizon Science Academy HS

6000 South Marginal Road

Cleveland, Ohio 44103

(216) 432-3660 x306

Email: nagelski@horizoncleveland.org